# **SASHA MILLER**

2458 W. Tokay St Lodi CA 95242 | (209) 224-7518 | sashazm85@gmail.com

# PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Front-End web developer with a focus on using semantic markup, scalable CSS and JavaScript to build highly performant and responsive websites. Specializing in turning design concepts into working themes in Drupal, Wordpress, and React. Involvement in local code meetups and developer conferences since 2013 has built a foundation of community collaboration resulting in constant improvements to both hard and soft skills.

### **SKILLS**

**Trilingual:** English, Russian, and Ukrainian

**Software:** Visual Studio Code, Windows, Git Bash, Adobe Photoshop **Languages:** JavaScript (ES5/6+), CSS/SASS, HTML, Twig, PHP (enough for theming)

**Frameworks/CMS:** Drupal 8, WordPress, Gatsby.js, React, GraphQL **Other:** OOP, Git, Gulp, Webpack, custom Wordpress plugin & Gutenberg block development, Node.js/NPM, Markdown, CSS Grid, Lando, Agile, CircleCl

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### Freelance Web Developer 2019 - Present

- Implement Responsive Web Design best practices to create performant websites usable on all devices and screen sizes
- Craft scalable (S)CSS architecture with BEM (Block, Element, Modifier) allowing easy maintenance through component scoping
- Utilize Gatsby.js to create JAMstack websites using React
- Build & maintain custom sites and themes in Drupal 8 and Wordpress
- Create custom Wordpress Gutenberg blocks in React to allow ease of content editing
- Follow team coding best practices using tools such as Git, ESLint and Prettier
- Automate end-to-end testing with Cypress and continuous integration using CircleCl

Homemaker 2007 - 2019

#### Private Nanny and Child Care 2002 - 2007

- Personal Nanny for 4 missionary children in Simferopol, Ukraine
- Planned and instructed educational activities
- Tutored older children in homework and Russian language

#### **EDUCATION**

## Crimean Regional Bible College Simferopol, Ukraine

- Graduated 2003 with a degree in Children's Ministry
- 4.92 GPA (5 point grading scale)

#### PORTFOLIO